

_

Details

Dubai
United Arab Emirates
+971567398804
mansoor.sadiq54321@gmail.com

Links

LinkedIn

Skills

PHP

Laravel Framework

Codeigniter

Third-party API Integration

RESTFUL APIs

JavaScript

Node.js

jQuery

XALA

HTML5 Bootstrap

CSS

MySQL

Cit

WebFlow

Wordpress

Agile Development

Languages

English

Profile

A highly motivated individual with in-depth knowledge of languages and development tools. Developed dashboards for applications and website management, developed android/IOS APIs for mobile applications, created database back-ends for five mobile apps using MySQL server, and worked in maintenance programs launched by the company. Regular attendee of web developer meetups and hackathons.

Employment History

 $Web/Backend\ Developer,\ Kaspar\ Consulting\ and\ Services,\ Johannesburg$

- Developed and managed user-friendly websites and dashboards with multiple user roles to handle the processes.
- Automated existing solutions to reduce time and workload
- Client requirements completion with technical aspects with new website solutions and applications
- Prioritizing software development projects, and setting timelines for given tasks
- Troubleshoot PHP, MySQL, and CSS issues related to websites
- Design and implement new features, enhancements, and content of existing websites improving performance and SEO.
- Web application programming interface (API) development for android and IOS applications
- For development used PHP Frameworks.
- Laravel and Codelgniter and worked with leading tools to enhance the coding experience according to standards
- Handled the functional development and performance optimization of the company's new and old products using the MVC technology stack.
- Created and integrated Application programming interfaces (API) for multiple mobile applications
- Linking web pages to 3rd party APIs
- Creating databases in MySQL and SQL frameworks for mobile applications for data handling and analysis
- Cooperating in the maintenance programs of the company's projects
- Redesigned old modules and interfaces to troubleshoot the user interfaces and long processes
- Refactor, optimize, and improve the existing code base for maintenance and scale.

Web Developer, Hi-Data Technologies, Islamabad

MARCH 2021 - MARCH 2022

- Completed the change requests for the clients and build new technical solutions for different market-based products
- Managing the directory and filing system for clients using the Laravel framework.
- Designing and building web applications using Laravel
- Testing functionality for users and the back end
- Integrating the 3rd party modules in existing modules
- Developed, recorded, and maintained cutting-edge web-based PHP applications and CMS systems
- Ensure HTML, CSS, and shared JavaScript is valid and consistent across applications
 Creating servers and databases for the functionality of web applications and

Intern, Pakistan Telecommunication Company Limited, Rawalpindi

JULY 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2019

CMS systems

- Basic training in MS Office, Excel, and Power BI for data handling and data entry purposes
- Trained with necessary tools to handle the data and improve the visibility of data patterns
- · Power BI integration for data analysis

Education

Bachelors, Foundation University, Islamabad

EPTEMBER 2015 - JUNE 2019

Bachelors in Software Engineering

